you might think that a weight bench is a
pretty basic piece of equipment and
while that might be true in a lot of
cases the right weight bench can
actually help take your workouts to the
next level that you're looking for the
force usa my bench is an fid bench which
stands for flat incline and decline it
comes with a leg roller attachment as
well as a preacher curl attachment that
some other companies are going to make
you pay extra for so there's a lot of
versatility here there's a lot to like
about this weight bench i've been using
this one for a while and i cannot wait
to share my findings with y'all
[Music]
what's up everybody it's jake you know
where i am the barbing garage gym and
guess what i've got another review ready
to go for y'all today this time it's the
force usa my bench in this video i'm
going to take you through everything
that you need to know about this weight
bench from the price to the features
some pros and cons that you'll
experience while working out with it as
well as who should or maybe should not
add this to their home gym now before i
really get going with everything today
we've reviewed a lot of weight benches
on barbin.com so if you want to browse
our best list just go ahead and search
barbin best weight benches and you can
find out for yourself which ones that we
like the
[Music]
best okay so what do i like about this
weight bench for starters it is about as
versatile of a weight bench as you could
ask for it all right so i already
mentioned it it's an fid bench if you
don't know what that means it stands for
flat incline and decline for a little
bit more reference here you can
absolutely use this for your incline
bench pressing obviously your flat bench
press as well as your decline bench and
since this leg roller attachment is here
it's you know it's set in place it's
going to keep my legs in place while i'm
doing a decline bench press and you can
even do some sit-ups with it if you
choose to now this is really going to be
great for leg development because it's
going to allow you to really focus on
your quads your glutes and your hammies
by doing leg curls as well as leg
extensions or you know
you could spend some time focusing on
your biceps with this preacher curl
attachment and that's super nice and it
even comes with the holder right here
for your barbell or ez curl bar whatever
you're using now it also has three
different adjustments for the seat pad
to go along with six adjustments for the
back pad so it's gonna give you you know
different angles for you to hit your
muscles on your body and it's rated up
to 700 pounds now that's including your
body weight that's still a pretty high
number for a weight bench so there's a
lot of heavy weight that you can lift on
this weight bench and because it does
have a handle as well as a set of wheels
it's going to make it pretty easy to
move around your home gym
okay so with all that being said there
have been a couple issues that i've ran
into personally while working out with
this weight bench and you also might run
into that so let's talk about that i'm
gonna start this off with the actual
size of this bench and if you can't tell
from watching me right now
it's kind of big all right so it's
pretty tall too so the height is just
under two feet it's around 22 22 and a
half inches or so and like i said you
know that's pretty tall it's taller than
some other weight benches that i've
worked out with and reviewed for you all
and when you have this leg roller
attached and it's the seat is in the
back pad everything's laid flat like i
have it right now
takes up over six feet of space and
obviously that's pretty big so
overall space with this weight bench
could be a problem and
because of that extra height you know if
you're a little bit shorter you might
have some issues when you go to get set
up for your bench press and you know
having your feet nice and flat so keep
that in mind and there is a bit of a gap
right here in between the the seat and
the back pad i personally don't like
that it gets a little annoying to me but
it's also pretty common with weight
benches and
only thing here is i wish it was a
little bit of a smaller gap but that
could also take away from some of the
versatility and you know by taking away
the adjustments that you could do with
this weight bench so that would probably
be a negative if they were to make that
gap a little bit smaller now you do have
a little bit of some steel right here
you got to deal with that it might dig
into your lower back a tiny bit if
that's a big problem for you
you could always throw an old t-shirt
down maybe a towel and that could
probably make things more comfortable
for you now as far as pricing goes it's
listed right around 400
i personally think that's a pretty good
deal considering you do have these extra
attachments
but 400 is still 400 and if you don't
want to spend that much money you could
definitely go find a cheaper one out
there but it's probably not going to be
as good of quality as this weight bench
is
and i doubt that it's going to come with
the you know the two attachments that we
have here with that original purchase
probably my least favorite thing was
putting this weight bench together
i did it by myself it took me about an
hour and a half maybe a little bit
longer and i think that would have been
sped up if i had somebody with me
so i would recommend having a partner to
help you out put this together i think
two hands or you know with this are
gonna make it go by faster but also for
your own sanity you know there's a lot
of little pieces here there's a lot of
things you gotta bolt together and you
know that could drive you crazy a little
bit especially if you're spending
over an hour because that's a pretty big
chunk of time so just keep that in mind
mentally prepare yourself for that
process before you start working out
with this weight bench
okay so let's talk a little bit more
about money now as i mentioned if you
head over to the force usa website
you'll find this weight bench to be
listed right around 400
once you tack on your shipping you're
looking at spending around 450
and yeah i know that's you know still
expensive but for what you're getting
here
a pretty solid deal in my opinion
there's other weight benches out there
that are more expensive than this one
and they don't feature any attachments
or they're not
compatible with any attachments so
that's something that force usa really
has got going on here with this weight
bench there's always a cheaper option
with any product out there right but
remember that's probably not going to
last you as long as this one will it's
probably not going to be as durable as
this one is
and i doubt that it's going to come with
the extra attachments like this one has
and if it's compatible with any you're
gonna have to add them on separately
most likely
and that's probably gonna make you spend
more money in the long run now
fortunately force usa does throw in a
lifetime warranty on the structural
frame of this weight bench which is a
nice touch it's going to cover any
manufacturing defects that might happen
and even if you want you can finance
this purchase through a firm and you'll
be making monthly payments of around 35
or so
okay so let's talk about the build now
with this weight bench as far as the
steel that was used for the framework
i'm not sure what gauge they used but i
gotta say it does feel really sturdy it
feels really durable the padding here
even including these leg rollers foam
padding it's pretty comfortable but it's
also firm in the places that it needs to
be firm so that's nice and as far as you
know overall space when you're working
out with this weight bench i'd recommend
around it nine square feet at least
because you know once again this is
taking up over six feet right now just
sitting here so that's something you
have to think about
before you try to add this to your home
gym and start working out with it
now let's talk about the features i'm
going to start with
this preacher curl attachment this also
has foam padding like i mentioned so
it's pretty comfortable on your arms as
you're going to do those curls there's
also a little holder right here or your
barbell or your easy curl bar whatever
you're using but you know i will say
it's kind of a bummer that this is not
lined with any type of plastic so you're
going to want to be careful you're not
going to want to just you know
carelessly drop your bar
into that holder because it could cause
some damage to your bar and i really
doubt that you want that
now when it comes to the leg roller
attachment this is great
obviously padding right here is also
made from foam
your weight horn right here that's made
from plastic
um but that's fine and if you're ever
worried about your plates possibly you
know sliding off while you're working
out with this there's also a clip that
you know comes with this weight bench so
that's nice it's just going to keep your
plates where they need to be and i don't
know if you can see it very well but
there's this u-shaped pin right here and
what this does it you pull it out and
it's going to lock into this hole right
here and that's going to keep this from
moving that's going to be great while
you're doing your decline bench press or
even if you're wanting to do some
sit-ups with this in that decline
position
that's really nice and as far as
adjusting the seat you know you have
three different adjustments it doesn't
go down like
a lot of
adjustable weight benches do
but i mean that's okay to me might not
be to you but that's something worth
mentioning to do that you can't see it
but there's this pin right here there's
a handle on the other side you just pull
it out that's going to allow you to
raise it up and put it where you want it
to be now when it comes to adjusting the
back pad there's a handle right here and
that's going to control this support
right here and adjust it into each one
of these ladder hooks for your workout
but you can also just grab the bench
itself if you want and just lift up that
back pad and that's totally easy
it's not very heavy i don't really know
how much it weighs i wouldn't say
more than 70 pounds or so with this
attached which is pretty nice you could
pick it up and move it if you wanted to
but fortunately you do have a set of
wheels as well as a handle down here for
you to slide it around your home gym
really
with ease but i will say when this leg
roller is attached
because of this top roller as well as
that weight horn right there can kind of
get in your way and be hard to reach
under and grab that handle so i would
recommend not having this in there
whenever you go to move it
and to adjust the height of the preacher
curl as well as this leg roller
attachment there's a little knob right
here and all you got to do is twist it
and pull it out i will say though that's
kind of hard to do because you can't see
the holes and where they line up because
of where it's located it'd be cool if it
was on the outside right here so you
could really you know get that precision
but that's not the case and you'll get
the hang of it eventually i kind of have
it's
still a little bit of a hassle but just
keep that in mind because it might take
you you know a couple tries to really
get good at it when you go to get set up
for your workouts
all right let's do a quick trip around
this weight bench now i'll go over some
of the details you know more up close
and personal let's start with the
padding
that foam padding i was talking about
it's pretty comfortable but it's also
firm at the same time which is a nice
touch you're gonna want that while i got
you here there is this little bit of an
awkward gap between the two pads
i personally don't like that you know
it's pretty common with the weight bench
i just wish it was a little bit you know
thinner of a gap right there because
i'll show you this in a second but when
this is in the decline position you
really got to deal with this support
right here you know possibly digging
into your lower back
not a whole lot you can do other than to
throw a towel or maybe an old t-shirt or
something to cover that up and to make
it more comfortable for you now let's
talk about the attachments
this preacher curl attachment is great
it's also got that foam padding right
here it's going to be really nice for
the back of your arms to rest on when
you're doing those curls you also have
this holder right here for your barbell
ez curl bar whatever you're using i just
wish it was lined with a plastic that
way it's going to prevent any damage
happening to your barbell so you're
going to want to be careful you don't
want to slam your bar in here it's going
to cause scratches you know any other
damage that you really want to avoid and
as far as adjustments go with the height
of your attachments both of them have
five different options for you to work
with it can be a little difficult to
find that sweet spot you know for your
workout but that's because the knob to
adjust everything is located in kind of
an awkward spot it's down here kind of
hidden you can't really see it and you
can't really find where the holes are
gonna line up together it'd be nice if
it was on this front side right here
but it's not and it's just gonna be
something you have to learn to work
through
might not be that bad though in the long
run okay so now let's talk about the leg
roller attachment which really is my
favorite thing about this weight bench
it's really nice when it comes to doing
those decline presses as well as doing
some sit-ups really any core work
because you have somewhere to put your
legs and to stay stable now as you can
see it's not moving right now it's
because there's this u-shaped pin it
goes into a hole just like this one on
the other side all you have to do slide
it out because there's a spring right
here
twist it up it's out of the way
now you're able to do those leg curls
and those leg extensions which is really
nice you can focus on your leg
development
now
there's your weight horn right here
there is a little bit of a bump from
where
i had to put that screw in to hold these
two pieces together that could be a
problem in itself because it could
prevent your weights from sliding all
the way down
and that's like an inch or so that's
like another inch that could be an extra
plate that you want to throw on that
you're not able to do
so that could be a little bit of a
trouble
if you're ever worried about your plates
sliding off don't worry anymore
this comes with a nice weight you know
clip clamp whatever you want to call it
right here squeeze it
slide it down your plates aren't going
to come off all right so up front right
here you also have this nice flat foot
design that i like it's going to add to
the stability of this weight bench and
also it doesn't really get in the way of
your feet too much which is a nice touch
when you're doing your bench presses
this is where your handle is located
pretty easy to grab for the most part i
wouldn't recommend having this attached
if you're going to move it around all
right so in terms of adjusting your seat
you have three different options to work
with as you can see there is a pin right
here
on my side there's a handle just pull on
it
you hear that noise you're able to
adjust it like i said you have three
different adjustments
some people might not like the fact that
this seat cannot angle downward like a
lot of adjustable weight benches are
able to do with their seat
i personally don't mind it but you know
you can't you don't have a choice
because
the support's right here it's in the way
it's not gonna allow you to do that so
something to remember if you're looking
to add this to your home now when it
comes to adjusting the back pad it's
pretty easy move that preacher curl out
of the way
now you have a handle right here that's
gonna be for this support right here as
you can see i mean all i have to do is
just lift right up on this you can put
it exactly where you want
on any of these ladder hooks right here
super easy to do now
when it comes to this decline position
there's that support i was talking about
as you can see it does kind of stick out
at you
and you know sometimes i feel it when
i'm using this for a decline bench
sometimes i don't
kind of just depends
if that's a big problem for you really
the only thing you can do is to throw an
old t-shirt down or
you know maybe a towel
it's really all you can do about it
it's okay
now back here i'll slide this up and get
out of the way
back here is also your wheels and you
also have two
flat
sides of this little support down here
that's gonna be super nice make it super
sturdy i mean i know i'm kind of making
this wobble on my own but it takes you
know a good amount of effort to do it i
don't think that's going to happen on
you while you're simply working out
[Music]
okay so who should purchase this weight
bench well
honestly in my opinion anybody looking
for a solid fid bench to add to their
home gym
this should be on your short list of
targets because it does come with this
allegro attachment as well as the
preacher curl attachment for a pretty
affordable price and that's kind of rare
in my opinion a lot of companies with
their adjustable weight benches they
don't offer
really any attachments and they're not
compatible with any attachments so this
is like i said it's kind of rare in my
opinion because you have so many
different angles you can hit out there's
a lot of versatility which really is the
biggest selling point in my opinion you
can do decline incline bench press like
i said focus on your bicep
focus on your you know targeting
different parts of your legs there's a
lot you can do with this weight bench it
can accommodate for a lot of different
things
and you know this really is going to
last you a long time i think because of
how stable sturdy durable you know
filling the blank this bench really is
and as long as you don't do anything
crazy with it i think it could last you
potentially a lifetime
[Music]
let's talk about money first you know i
personally think spending around 450 for
this bench it's a pretty solid deal
considering the versatility as well as
the attachments that are included with
that purchase
however if this does fall out of your
budget you can find yourself a cheaper
one out there but i said it once i'm
gonna say it again it's not guaranteed
that those cheaper options are gonna
come with attachments in that original
purchase and they also you know i can't
speak to the quality of those weight
benches it's not guaranteed that they're
going to last you as long as this bench
could potentially last you
and that's something you got to think
about overall spacing is going to be an
issue for people too so
like i said this takes up over six feet
right now and if you don't have a whole
lot of space to work with
this probably isn't going to be the best
fit for your home gym
and it is pretty tall you know it's just
under two feet tall so if you are
a little bit shorter you might have some
issues when you go to get set up for
that bench press you got to get your
feet nice and flat on the ground and
trying to drive those heels into the
ground that might create a bit of a
problem for you if your feet can't touch
the ground
and while 700 pounds weight rating might
be great for a lot of you personally
it's fine for me that is including body
weight but i don't really need a weight
bench that you know can handle more
weight than that personally
now if you are a power lifter you're
bench pressing some super heavy weight
this might not be it for you because you
know
might not be able to handle as much
weight as you're pressing so keep that
in mind you might want to go and explore
some other options that are going to be
able to hold up to that weight
that you're being able to lift
[Music]
all right y'all that's a wrap for
today's review over the force usa my
bench i personally love it i think it
could be your next great purchase to
kind of complete your home gym it's an
fid bench so it's really versatile also
you know it does come with this preacher
curl and leg roller attachment which
this those are just two great additions
gonna add to that versatility even more
and really spice things up in your
weight room it can handle up to 700
pounds which is pretty solid and it's
really durable i think it's going to
last you a really long time but with the
weight rating remember that is including
your body weight so some of those power
lifters out there watching
might not be the one for you and it does
dominate a good amount of space so if
you're already tight on space this also
might not be a good fit for you and this
i don't think it should turn you away
from this bench but remember it's gonna
take you a while to assemble it at least
an hour maybe longer just keep that in
mind stay patient it'll be worth it in
my opinion thanks for watching everybody
hope this video was helpful i hope that
i was able to answer some questions that
you might have over this weight bench or
maybe even showed you a few things that
you hadn't even thought of yet as always
stay on the lookout for my next review
but for now you should absolutely head
over to barbin.com and you can read more
about this product just google barbend
force usa my bench review and you can
read about everything i talked about
here today
i'll see y'all next time
[Music]
you